<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Saisyam - My Blog</title>
    <link>https://saisyam.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Saisyam - My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saisyam.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis using Python Vader</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/sentiment-analysis-using-python-vader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/sentiment-analysis-using-python-vader/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing the emotions of the customers will help product and service companies to improve their quality. Sentiment Analysis helps in identifying these emotions computationally without any manual intervention. In this article we are not discussing the underlying process of identifying the sentiment, but we use a pre-built engine to process our text.
VADER is a rule-based sentiment analysis tool written in Python to analyze a given text. VADER not only tells about the positivity and negativity score but also tells us about how positive or negative it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrape web content with 2 Popular Python packages</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/scrape-web-content-with-2-popular-python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/scrape-web-content-with-2-popular-python-packages/</guid>
      <description>Information is wealth. Today there is tremendous amount of data online. There are thousands of crawlers scrape web daily to collect information and process them. In this article we see 2 popular tools to easily extract content from the webpages.
Why scrape web We have lot of data online in the form of websites. Websites include HTML content and JavaScript. We need specific parsers to parse the HTML content and extract information into meaningful buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Files as Gists in webpage</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/github-files-as-gists-in-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/github-files-as-gists-in-webpage/</guid>
      <description>Including Github Gists into a webpage is a common practice. But sometimes I would like to add a source file from one of my repos (public repos) into the webpage instead of splitting the file into multiple gists.
I write technical blogs which involve lots of code to be shown and explained as you are reading now. I want to embed any source file from my public Github repo into my webpage or my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading CSV File in Python</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/reading-csv-file-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/reading-csv-file-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Today data is available in various formats, like, CSV, JSON, TXT etc. Python provides all the necessary tools to parse these files. In this article we will learn how to parse a large CSV file using Python.
We will use Python csv package and pandas to parse the CSV file. I have taken a CSV file of baby names from here. This file contains 250K records of baby names. I am using this data to generate user database to test the login API I have built.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
