<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>splinter on Saisyam - My Blog</title>
    <link>https://saisyam.com/tags/splinter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in splinter on Saisyam - My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saisyam.com/tags/splinter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scrape web content with 2 Popular Python packages</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/scrape-web-content-with-2-popular-python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/scrape-web-content-with-2-popular-python-packages/</guid>
      <description>Information is wealth. Today there is tremendous amount of data online. There are thousands of crawlers scrape web daily to collect information and process them. In this article we see 2 popular tools to easily extract content from the webpages.
Why scrape web We have lot of data online in the form of websites. Websites include HTML content and JavaScript. We need specific parsers to parse the HTML content and extract information into meaningful buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proven way to Fake Webcam in Test Automation with Python</title>
      <link>https://saisyam.com/proven-way-to-fake-webcam-in-test-automation-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saisyam.com/proven-way-to-fake-webcam-in-test-automation-with-python/</guid>
      <description>We automate web application testing using Python Selenium or Splinter. How will you automate testing applications with webcam? You can fake a webcam device with Chrome Web driver. In this article we will see how to do that.
Challenge The challenge here is to fake the webcam with proper video format. In this post I am using Chrome browser along with Splinter. If you are new to Splinter, check out my article and I promise you love it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
